Guide to the International Labor Rights Forum Archive, 1986-2016 LAC0019
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Labor Rights Forum
1986-2016
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
LAC0019
55.5 Linear Feet 37 record cartons
This collection consists of materials relating to the ILRF's work in monitoring the labor components of American trade agreements with other countries. Materials include reports, legislation, correspondence and publications pertaining to labor relations and workers' rights in the countries of trading partners.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in eleven series: country files, GSP general files, reports, US government files, subject files, financial files, donor files, International Labor Organization files, campaign research, miscellaneous files, and audiovisual files.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated by the Internatioanl Labor Rights Forum in December 2016.
Biographical / Historical
The International Labor Rights Forum is a human rights organization dedicated to advocating for labor rights worldwide. The ILRF works with trade unions, local community groups, and faith-based organizations to support workers. The IRLF strives to hold international corporations accountable for labor rights violations, advance policies that benefit and protect workers' rights, and assist in strengthening worker self-advocacy. Some of the main issues the ILRF focuses on include child labor, forced labor, health and safety, women's rights, precarious work, living wage, migrant labor, and the right to organize and bargain. In the early 1980's concerned activists formed a coalition to fight for the rights of workers in international trade. In 1984, the coalition succeeded in securing the first labor rights clause in the Generalized System of Preferences. This labor rights clause would connect US trade and investment benefits to the respect of labor rights in other countries. In 1986, the coalition launched the International Labor Rights Forum to monitor the enforcement of international labor laws. The ILRF has leD and supported a number of initiatives such AS improving factory safety in Bangladesh, stopping the exploitation of children in the cotton fields of Uzbekistan, increasing the income of farm workers in the cocoa fields of West Africa, developing labor law clinics in China, advocating for increased labor rights provisions in US legislation, improving the conditions of seafood workers in Thailand, promoting fair labor principles in the palm oil industry, and supporting threatened union leaders in Latin America's banana sector. In 1990, the ILRF formed the Alliance for Responsible Trade with allied North American advocacy groups to demand transparency and labor rights provisions in NAFTA. In 1994, the ILRF founded RugMark (now GoodWeave International), a nonprofit organization that has moved over 3,000 children out of the carpet industry and provided them with education. In 2010, ILRF merged with SweatFree Communities and founded the SweatFree Purchasing Consortium, which incorporated labor rights into city and state procurement policies. In 2013, U.S. Labor Education in the Americas Project became part of the ILRF. The U.S. Labor Education in the Americas Project (USLEAP) advocates for fundamental changes to U.S. trade policies, demands corporate responsibility, denounces violence against trade unionists, and campaigns for worker justice in agro-export industries in Latin America.
Scope and Contents
The collections consists of reports, correspondenece, legislative materials and publications pertaining to the work of the ILRF in monitoring U.S. trade agreements for maintenance of positive labor relations and workers' rights in the countries of U.S. trading partners.
Bib#
17257791
Labor unions; International relations; International Labor Rights Forum
- Country Files, Series 1
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by country.
  - Thailand, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Thailand, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Thailand, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Thailand, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Thailand, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Thailand, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Turkey, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Turkey, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - United States, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Uzbekistan, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Pakistan ILRF Corresponse, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Pakistan GOP Response, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Panama, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Panama, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Paraguay, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Peru, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Peru, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Peru, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Peru and Panama FTA Texts, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Sri Lanka, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Sri Lanka, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Sri Lanka, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Syria, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Syria, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Syria, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Sudan, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Taiwan, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Taiwan, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Thailand, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Thailand, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Malaysia Petition, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Malaysia Case, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Malaysia USTR Response, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Maldives, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Mauritania, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Mexico, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Mexico, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Mexico Petition Rejection Response, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Nepal, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Niger, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Niger, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Niger, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Nigeria, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Oman, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Pakistan, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Pakistan, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pakistan, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Pakistan ILRF Case, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pakistan, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Pakistan Government Response, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Indonesia ILRF Correspondence, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Indonesia Submissions, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Indonesia Morsinah Report, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Indonesia Government Response, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Indonesia, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Indonesia ILRF Correspondence, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Indonesia, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Israel, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Korea, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Korea, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Korea, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Korea, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Korea, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Liberia, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Liberia, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Malaysia, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Malaysia, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Malaysia IBEW Letter, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Malaysia, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Malaysia, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Guatemala, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Guatemala, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Haiti, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Haiti, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Haiti, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Haiti, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Honduras, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Honduras, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - India- Post Meeting Briefs, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - India, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Indonesia, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Indonesia, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Indonesia, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Indonesia, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Indonesia ILRF Correspondence, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Indonesia ILRF Case, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Indonesia USTR Response, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Indonesia Defense, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Indonesia Government Rebuttal, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Indonesia Company Testimonies, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - El Salvador, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - El Salvador, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - El Salvador, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - El Salvador, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - El Salvador, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - El Salvador Fenastres Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - El Salvador Internal Memos, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - El Salvador, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - El Salvador USTR Response, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - El Salvador, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - El Salvador- Sugar, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Guatemala, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Guatemala, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Guatemala, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Guatemala, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Guatemala- Government Meeting, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Guatemala- Post Meeting Briefs, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Guatemala, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Guatemala, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Guatemala, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Algeria, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Belarus, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bangladesh, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bangladesh, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bangladesh, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Benin, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Burma, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cambodia, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cambodia, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Central African Republic, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chile, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chile, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chile, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Colombia, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Colombia, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Colombia FTA, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Costa Rica, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dominican Republic, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dominican Republic, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Zaire, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Labor Conditions in the Costa Rican Sugar Industry Reports, 2005 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Firestone Agricultural Worker's Union of Liberia Files, 2005-2007 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Firestone Agricultural Worker's Union of Liberia Files, 2007-2008 (Box 38, Folder 3)
- GSP General Files, Series 2
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - GSP General Review, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - GSP General Review, 1987-1988; ` (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - GSP Petitions, General or Multi-country, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - GSP Petitions, General, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - GSP General, 1985-1995 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - GSP Petitions, General, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - GSP Annual Review, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - GSP Review, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - GSP Petition and General Review, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - GSP Reform, Old, 1994-2008 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - GSP Petitions, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Trade Preference Reform, 2009-2011 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - GSP General, Filings and USTR Notices, 1997-2007 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - GSP General Filing, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - GSP General, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - GSP Hearing, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Reports, Series 3
  This series is arranged by subject.
  - International Labor Standards Paper for Human Rights Organization by Kerry Kircher (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - GSP Petitions, Philippines, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - GSP Petitions, Philippines, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - GSP Petitions, Philippines, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - GSP Petitions, Philippines, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Writ of Ampano, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Remigio Saladero Files, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Sumifra Bananas Report, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dole Background Research, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Reports, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - National Community Reinvestment Coalition Reinvestment Works Publication, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Resource Center of the Americas, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Mother Jones, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Faith Works, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Far Eastern Economic Review, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous Short Articles/Reports, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - US Business Principles for Human Rights of Workers in China Report, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - FLASH Inter-American Region, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Mexican Information Service for Social Justice Review, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Human Rights Workers, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Asian Workers Newsletter, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - GEO Grassroots Economic Organizing, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - As the South Goes by Institute for the Elimination of Poverty and Genocide, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Linking Issues Networks for Cooperations, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Gender and Trade Articles, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Background Reports, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - GSP Philippines, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - ILAB- Trade Reference Research, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - ILRF Summary of Progress, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - China- Labor Movement Report, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Korea Church Coalition Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty Report, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Food First Action Alert: Institute for Food and Development Policy, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Spotlite on Recent Publications, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Update: The World Bank, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Informe Anual, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Workers Rights News, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - IMF Survey Publications, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Democracy Backgrounder, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Canadian HR Foundation, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Interconnect, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - FIAN International, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE) Digest, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Foreign Policy in Focus, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - The Kyodan Missionary Bulletin, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Children and Work, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - IUF North America Labor Link, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Justicing, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - The KPF Newsletter, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Working Together Labor Report on the Americas, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - NAO, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - GSP Studies, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Labor Rights Delegation Feasibility Studies, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - ARPLA- Labor Administration Bulletin, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Mariana Islands Reports, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mariana Islands Reports, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Japan Reports, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Asian-Pacific News, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Extra! A Publication of FAIR, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Global Electronics Newsletter, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Asia Link, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Human Rights Monitor, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Asian Food Worker, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondencia, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Environmental Bulletin, World Bank, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Echoes from Tiananmen, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - ILO Washington Focus, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Global Exchange Reports, 1991-1997 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Resource Center Bulletin, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Federation for Industrial Retention and Renewal News, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - IMADR Bulletin, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- US Government Files, Series 4
  This series is arranged by government agency or by subject.
  - DOEN, 2007-2008 (Box 27, Folder 46)
  - Codes of Conduct Legislation, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Debt Crisis, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Migrant/Seasonal Farmworkers Research, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Global Sustainable Development Resolution, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - OPIC, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - OPIC Laws, Regulations, and Correspondence, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - OPIC Hearing, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 41)
  - NAO General, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - NAO Responses, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - NAO Case 94003 Sony, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Department of Labor Court Hearings- Sony, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - NAO Complaint 940004 G.E. Elections, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - NAO Case 96001 - Fisheries, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - DeCoston Egg Farm Case, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Washington State Apple Case, 1998-1999 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - NAO Case 9702 Han Young, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - "Peerless" NAO Case, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - NAO Complaint 940001 Honeywell, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - NAO Complaint 940002 GE, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Bonded Child Labor Ban AEF, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - General Advocacy in Asia, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - C. 182 Work Groups, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Department of Labor Child Labor Hearings, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Child Labor in Mexico, 2002 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - DOL GSP Individual Research Project, 2010-2012 (Box 27, Folder 47)
  - DOL, 2010 (Box 27, Folder 48)
  - Department of Labor General, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - USAID, 1999-2000 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - USAID Project Finances, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Counterpart (USAID, GCSS), 2008-2009 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - GCSS, 2010 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - USAID Project, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - AED-GCSS through USAID, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - USAID, 2003 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - USAID Negotiated Indirect Cost Rate Agreement, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - GCSS AED, 2007-2008 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - USAID Financial Report, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Department of Labor Financial General, 1999-2001 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - China #037, 2010 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - OPIC Legislation, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - OPIC Hearings, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - OPIC Testimony, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - OPIC Hearings Malaysia, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - OPIC Hearings Taiwan, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - State Department Bureau of Democracy China Labor Watch, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - State Department Proposals, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - State Department China RFP, 2009 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Free2Work, 2009 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - State Department China 007 - Closed, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - China - 611, 2007-2011 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - China - 187, 2007-2011 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - China - 570, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - New State China Proposal, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - China Grant #550, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Department of Labor Child Labor Hearing Statement, 1995 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - DRL Program, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - DRL Proposal re: Philippines, 2010 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - DRL Proposal: ILRF "Promoting Rules of Law in China's Labor Relations System", 2008 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - DRL Interest China Statement, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Child Labor Research, 2009 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Department of Labor Trade Preferences Research Contract, 2011 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Department of Labor Forced Labor, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Department of Labor Standards Project Grants, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Department of Labor Procedures, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - NAALC Research, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Canadian Postal Rural Route Couriers, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ways and Means Committee, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - CBI Act, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Ways and Means Committee Hearing, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - UE Amicus Brief, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Brown Social Charter Resolution, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Torres Resolution American Development Bank, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Labor in Mexico, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - NAALC Original, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - US Congress NAFTA Opinions, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - NAFTA Canada, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - GSP Bill Campaign, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Latinos for NAFTA, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Trade Unionism and NAFTA, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Speech on Europe and NAFTA, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Congress Progressive Caucus, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Indonesia Jam, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - House Trade Subcommittee Hearing on GSP, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - AU Conference on NAFTA, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Ottowa NAFTA Consultations, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Forced Labor Cases, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - US Bills, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - NAO Case 9701- Sexual Harrassment, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - NAALC-NAO General, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Trade Bill, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Pharis Harvey Prepared Statement, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Trade Sanctions Bill, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Pharis Harvey Prepared Statement, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Telephone Memos, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Senate Finance Committee Testimony, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - GSP Lawsuit ILRF v. Bush, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - NAFTA Mexico Opposition Statements, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Workman Resolution, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Legislation, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - ADA Lawsuit: Appeal, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - GSP Government Appeal Brief, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - National Safe Workplace Institute, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Pease Resolution, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Gephardt, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - US Congress, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - NAFTA US Labor Statements, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - NAFTA Private Sector Statements, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Congressional Fair Trade Caucus, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Jontz Resolution, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - DOL Garment Industry, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - USTR, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Senate Finance Committee Statements, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - DOL USA Profile, 1988-1995 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Securities/Exchange Commission, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Department of Treasury, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - NAO- General Labor Law and International Relations Conference, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - DOL Grants, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - US/LEAP Board Reports, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - DOL Releases, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Export/Import Bank, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Department of Interior, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - 1974 Trade Act (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - GSP Legislation, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - GSP Pease Bill, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Trade Sub Committee Hearings, 1984-1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - US Senate Committee on Finance Statement, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Fair Trade Bill, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Fair Trade Bill Hearings, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Senate Finance Committee Hearings, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs Letter, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Women's Garment Industry Report, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Legislation- Nonresident Workers Act and Alien Labor Rules and Regulations, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Department of Commerce Users Guide to Information, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Department of Justice, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - INS-DOL MOU Case, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Guatemala Worker v. INS Litigation, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - HR 1445 Maquiladoras Bill, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - DOL Proposal: Workforce Security Act of 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - HR 2295-2333 Aid Authorization Bill, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous US Aid Bills, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - DOL Hearing, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - NAO Complaints, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - National Labor Relations Board 4 Year Report, 1994-1998 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - ILA Court Case, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - HR 1050 A Living Wage for All Act, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Sony Press Conference, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - DOL No Sweat Initiative, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - DOL Child Labor Public Hearing, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - US National Administrative Office Report on Ministerial Consultations, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Subject Files, Series 5
  - China Business Principles Correspondence, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - China Proposal, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - China SED, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - China 605, 2010 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - US-China Principles Chinese Version, ND (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Korean Manufacturers in China, ND (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - China Footwear, 1994-1997 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - China Campaigns Policy Options, 1994-2000 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - China Toy Industry, 1995-1998 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - China Women Workers, 1995-1999 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - China Garment Industry, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - China Amnesty Reports, 1996-1999 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - China Labor Rights Activists, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 10)